A Guide to the Astoria Beneficial Club/Richmond Beneficial Insurance Archives 1906-1947
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Astoria Beneficial Club/Richmond Beneficial Insurance Archives 1906-1947
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 311
.36 linear feet
Astoria Beneficial Club
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection is on loan to Special Collections and Archives from the Astoria Beneficial Club through Dr. Francis Foster, a member of the club. VCU does not hold copyright. Accession number EM 1
Historical Information
Astoria Beneficial Club (ABC) began as a social club in 1901, but eventually became a beneficial club that paid out sick dues and burial benefits to its members. Astoria donated money to organizations that benefitted the community, such as the NAACP and the local Colored YMCA, and to individuals in need. The Club also set up scholarships at Virginia Union University and honored individuals and businesses in the area for their community service. The Astoria Beneficial Club is still active in Richmond.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes minutes, correspondence, committee reports and other materials. The date range of these archives spans the years 1906 to 1947. The minutes are from the years 1906 to 1909, 1911 to 1927, 1935 to 1941, 1943, and 1947. There are minutes missing from each of the above years.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Items are arranged chronologically.
Organization
The collection is organized alphabetically by subject.
Contents List
- Applications for Membership 1921-1922 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Bills (Box-folder 1:2)
- Board of Directors Reports 1925, 1936 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Board of Governors Reports 1921, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Certificates of Sickness 1922, 1923, 1926 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Charities Committee Reports 1942 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Club Night Committee Report 1936 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Correspondence with members 1924, 1926, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Correspondence Miscellaneous 1928, 1930, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Excursion Committee Report 1924, 1927 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Gavagan Anti-lynching Bill Correspondence 1937 (Box-folder 1:12)
- Minutes 1906-1947 (Box-folder 1:13)
  Coverage: 1906-1909, 1911-1927. Random minutes for 1906, 1915, 1921-1922, 1927, 1935-1941, 1943, 1947.
- Race Relations and the Richmond News Leader1938 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Requests for Donations 1915, 1927-1937 (Box-folder 1:15)
- Sick Committee Reports 1913, 1916,1919, 1923, 1927, 1931, 1935 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Virginia Union University 1927, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 1:17)